You've eaten at McDonald's. But you've
never seen its biggest business:
$10.4 billion a year, from
something you can't eat.
It's rent. About 95% of McDonald's
restaurants are run by franchisees.
And most of them pay rent… to McDonald's.
In its biggest markets, McDonald's
owns the land under more than half its
restaurants, and about
80% of the buildings.
The royalties on all those burgers?
About $6 billion. The rent? $10.4 billion.
Back in the fifties, its finance chief
Harry Sonneborn put it like this:
We are not technically
in the food business.
We are in the real estate business.
The burger gets you in the door.
The door is what they own.
Your Big Mac pays the rent.